Billy Baggerman



bill.baggerman@gmail.com



404.502.0848



linkedin.com/in/BillBaggerman



github.com/bbag

Don't let my Marketing titles give the wrong impression!

For the past 9 years, every role I've worked in has been a developer/ marketer hybrid, and has had me hands-on writing code, building customer-facing interfaces, and working directly alongside agile dev

When I find myself geeking out on Raspberry Pi projects, learning Vue & React for coding up fun personal ideas, and using web development every chance I get in my marketing career, it makes me realize that frontend development is where I want to be.

Now, I'm looking to make that jump to front-end development full time!

Skillset

Frontend Development

































UX/UI Design







Xd Adobe XD



Portfolio:

https://bbag.github.io

Work Experience

Developer Marketing, Principal Product Mktg. Mgr. Axway, Inc.

July 2019 - Present



- Served as a hybrid Developer/Marketer role, leading Axway's developer strategy and working closely with technical and product teams to advance Axway's Amplify platform.
- Built a reactive Theme Creator web app with Vue.js for rapidly designing and previewing mobile applications built with Titanium Mobile.
- Designed all UX/UI elements, interactions, and flows for the Griffin App Axway's official internal app for helping employees return to work safely following COVID-19.
- Designed and coded a flexible, customizable, responsive header component to be consumed by other developers at Axway, in order to help standardize the header navigation across all Axway portals for a more consistent user experience.
- Led Axway's developer-focused marketing initiatives, including revamping developer landing pages, building out developer-targeted content and resources, and writing for the Axway Developer Blog.
- 2nd place in Axway's 2020 #BetterConnected hackathon, designing the layout & flow for an API-driven mobile application for connecting with your neighbors and community, showcasing features of Axway's entire SaaS integration platform.

Freelance Frontend Developer (Vue, Wordpress) Freelance

October 2017 - Present



- Helped clients in a variety of industries ranging from healthcare, fitness, eCommerce, and technology optimize their entire web presence; everything from website creation/optimization to brand development, content creation to sales funnel strategies, and more.
- Client projects have included full website design and creation from scratch, as well as inheriting existing designs and WordPress codebases to further develop.
- Worked with clients end-to-end until project completion, from initial wireframing, to mocking up UX flows in Adobe XD, and ultimately turning designs into code.

Senior Creative & Digital Marketing

Digital Envoy, Inc.

June 2014 - June 2019



- Led Digital Envoy's digital marketing initiatives, including directing PR and Design teams to launch and promote new marketing content pieces across our digital channels, and coordinating those teams with Marketing and Sales to meet the company's ambitious sales objectives.
- Led the redesign and launch of the Digital Element website, making analytics-based UX decisions to better drive site engagement and lead generation (resulting in 3x weekly traffic levels since being brought on).
- Built and optimized new landing pages across the old and new sites, which grew conversion rates by over 140%.
- Completely redesigned and rebuilt the Customer Support Portal for a greatly enhanced user experience.

Creative Services Intern

January 2012 - May 2012



Designed and built mobile web apps for Proximus' clients, including Walgreens, Toys"R"Us, and Chick-Fil-A, intended for on-site ad promotions to customers.

Education

Proximus Mobility LLC

University of Georgia, Terry College of Business

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

December 2018



Georgia State University



